[ Watch on kissFlix.co ]
Oh, sir. What a precious gift.
-Can it truly be mine?
-Uh-huh.
Leave him be. He's delighted, eh?
Dear cousin,
have you ever seen a map drawn
by an Italian named Matteo Ricci?
I confess, it took me quite a while
to find where Joseon was on it.
Joseon, which had always seemed
so large and definite,
suddenly felt small.
In truth, it was a fearful revelation.
For how small must I be,
living in my small corner of Hwaseong?
A letter!
Bring it here!
A letter for the young lady
in Minister Cho's house!
Here.
I have opened a map of Joseon
that was drawn here hundreds of years ago.
By the standards of Western learning,
Joseon is certainly
the wrong size on this map.
And yet, I have found myself questioning,
is this map truly wrong?
Perhaps the mapmaker wished
to capture the hearts of the people
who stood on this small land.
As I continue to reflect,
these two Joseons have prompted me
to realize something further.
Whether the land beneath us
is small or large,
we see the world through our eyes,
and they see the world through theirs.
Such is the way of it.
Just as I am simply myself,
and you are simply yourself.
What do you think?
You may call it sophistry,
but I am very curious to hear what
my literary friend makes of such thoughts.
I await your reply.
Be straight and steadfast.
And keep the way of the gentleman.
Do you understand?
Be straight
and steadfast.
Steadfast.
My father passed away so suddenly.
There is no way
to stop the sorrow rising within me.
I still need my father here.
I wanted him to see me become
the kind of son he could be proud of,
but now it is too late.
Dear cousin,
what am I to do?
I am sorry that I cannot
fully fathom the pain you are in.
But, Won,
even if I may be the only one
to tell you this,
you must know
you are more than just the son
your father wanted you to be.
You must find yourself,
rather than chasing after someone else.
I know my words may not reach you
at the moment.
I am me,
and you are you.
Mmm.
Hmm.
How wonderfully indecent.
Madam.
Lady Cho, the wife of Minister Yoo,
is here to see you.
She may enter.
Even in this undyed state,
it gives off a most lustrous sheen.
I may go so far as to say
this silk resembles you, my lady.
The tobacco you sent over
was more than enough.
You needn't have brought me this as well.
My most humble thanks.
I will say, it is gratefully received.
I am most humbled by your words.
I was a bit unsure of my welcome here.
In truth, I feared you may have been
displeased by my cousin's failings.
I was so troubled,
I hardly slept last night.
So I see.
It could hardly have been
an easy decision,
as you are his cousin.
Yet, for a moral lady such as yourself,
there could be no other course
than to immediately come
in the deep hours of the night
and inform me, the Left State Councilor,
and our young In-ho.
I need hardly mention,
the chaste daughter-in-law
residing in this house.
We all thank you, my lady.
This morning,
I impressed upon In-ho that while study
is a commendable occupation,
it is best to do it by oneself.
Hence, he will not be bothering
your cousin anymore.
Your words bring me comfort.
Though I confess with some reservations.
Hmm? Which are?
While I am fond of the girl,
and I would like to trust her
to do what is right,
I must remind you that
when my cousin is involved, well,
he is no ordinary gentleman.
I am aware.
What with his reputation…
…and the exceptional impression
he makes in person.
Who could fail to draw such a conclusion?
If I may make a suggestion.
In the end, they are but
a young man and lady, are they not?
Though a lamp casts two shadows,
in the night,
all boundaries may disappear.
Perhaps it would be safer
to keep them apart from each other
for the time being?
Even if the separation be made by force.
Hmm.
I humbly apologize. I was too bold.
Come now.
There's no need for all that.
Huh…
If you continue like this,
I shall be put out.
Good heavens.
If my lord husband were to see this,
I should be in for a scolding.
Now raise those eyes.
Come now.
How is your husband, by the way?
How has his career been faring?
Quite well.
Though if the councilor
were to summon him,
he would be most grateful.
Hmm.
My dear! My dear!
My dear!
My dear wife.
Excellent news.
The Left State Councilor has summoned me.
I am to visit court.
Oh, how long it has been.
Too long.
But it would appear by this, the councilor
has not forgotten your ability.
I have you to thank, my lady.
You have been calling
on the Lady of the First Rank
nearly every day.
I am well aware.
No, surely it was not that.
My noble wife.
Dearest lady.
Listen…
The truth is,
I am well aware
that I am the reason
we have not sired an heir.
The failure is mine alone.
I knew it was futile, but nevertheless,
I took in a concubine.
It weighs mightily upon my heart
that I cannot fulfill your wishes.
Especially as you are always
tirelessly striving for my sake.
My lord, do not speak in this manner.
So-ok will prove herself
equal to the task.
Of one thing I am certain,
you will sire a strong heir.
Truly?
Indeed. If my lady says it,
then it must be so.
I shall prove to the entire household
that I am yet a man, hale and hearty!
Put me down, my lord.
-You'll hurt yourself!
-I am feeling younger already!
-My lady.
-Pray, put me down.
Mind your step.
Forgive me, miss.
You.
Yes?
Uh…
Where are you headed?
Uh, I was just out for a walk.
Uh, I heard the moon was nice.
Oh.
Who is it?
The person you are attempting to meet
under this lovely moon?
-Oh, no one. I--
-Uh-uh!
Do not lie.
It was Young Master In-ho.
This is a sketch
based on what I saw in a book.
It's an alarm clock.
It allows one to know the time
by looking with the eye.
This position means
a quarter hour past 9:00.
The single drumbeat earlier
told us it was 7:00,
which is shown thus.
And soon,
they will signal 9:00.
I shall be listening as well,
but we must take care not to miss it.
Go stand outside the gate,
and when they beat the drum twice,
you must come tell me at once.
Yes, sir.
-Two beats of the drum.
-Mmm.
My lord.
So you planned to meet
when these hands
were stretched out like the horizon?
Y-Yes.
I have no words
to express my astonishment.
Please! I humbly apologize, my lord.
I meant nothing by it.
You do realize
I'm duty-bound to inform my brother-in-law
and cousin about this matter.
But I would be most troubled
if I had to betray the Young Master In-ho.
It seems to honor my loyalty,
I must go against my duty.
Oh, how curious.
Why have you come so early?
What?
I know but little about this device here,
but is there not ample time remaining
for the hands to stretch out horizontally?
Huh?
What? I could have sworn it was…
You carry it
without knowing how to read it?
Oh, no. I know how to read it, of course.
I'm sure you do.
I really do know.
I admit that today
I'm greatly troubled,
and my mind is unsettled.
I shall therefore pretend
I have not seen you here.
Do you really mean it, my lord?
You would do well
not to draw attention by wandering.
Wait till the agreed time.
You may occupy yourself
by reading Elementary Learning aloud.
I shall be listening outside
to see if I can hear you.
Elementary Learning?
You don't even know that?
Uh, yes, I-I know it.
It's just…
Just what?
Well…
I shall alert my cousin.
I'm going. I'm going. I'm going, my lord.
Young Master In-ho, you say?
What to make of that?
If I can get him to wait, So-ok could…
What an utter mess.
Young master, the hour is 9:00.
Hmm.
"Once a girl has reached the age of ten,
she ought to refrain from going out.
She must listen to her teacher and mother
with meekness and follow their teachings.
She should be engaged in tending of hemp"…
Hmm? Oh.
…"raising silkworms,
spinning thread, weaving silk,
and braiding silk sash among other"…
I was reading it! I read it!
Huh?
Oh, no. Oh, no. Young master…
What?
Huh?
Surely not.
He could not have left
simply because I was slightly late.
Um…
Why did you not meet me last night?
What?
Um…
I was most certainly there.
I'm sure you were.
And you could not wait a moment.
I understand.
The fault is all mine.
I have committed a most grievous offense!
Oh, I didn't mean
to suggest it was your fault.
I know what you thought.
You thought you could dismiss
a woman such as I.
Dismiss you? That's preposterous.
-Absolutely untrue.
-It is not untrue!
You're dismissing me
because I am a concubine!
A what?
Are you…
Huh? What?
Hmm?
-Hello, my lord.
-There you are.
His Majesty had summoned me
on a matter of great importance.
-Oh?
-On my way back from the palace,
I bought this for you.
Oh. They're yakgwa.
-Mmm.
-Oh, my lord, thank you so much for this.
Of course.
Mmm.
-Say, "Ah."
-Ah.
Mmm.
Mm-hmm.
Now, my dear,
I must leave Bukchon for a while.
Huh?
I shall not be absent for long.
While I'm away, mind the madam's teachings
and learn the conduct of a young lady.
Mmm.
As soon as I return,
I will make you my concubine at once.
-Understood?
-You mean it?
Oh, yes.
I'd be ever so grateful, my lord.
This wretched hat.
It will soon be
Princess Hyegyeong's 60th birthday.
Hwaseong will host the banquet.
His Majesty entrusted it to me.
I shall show you, my lady,
how resolutely I will make use…
…of the opportunity you have provided.
Dear cousin,
would you be so good as to stay with us,
just for the time
while your brother-in-law is away?
You must have many questions to ask of me.
Now, the young widow, what did she say?
I have no way of knowing what she said.
Since you sent that filthy letter,
I have not caught so much as
a glimpse of the young lady's skirt.
Indeed,
who could fathom the state
of the lady's heart at present?
I can only hope she's still in possession
of her mind.
Who knows?
Perhaps no one.
Could it be, she read the letter
and became so overcome with lust,
she lost her mind?
Goodness, I must resolve
to be virtuous from now on.
My So-ok has entered Bukchon.
Her mother should bear herself
as befits her station.
My, oh, my.
You are more naive than I thought.
If you knew how the ladies in Bukchon
entertained themselves,
you would faint dead away.
-What do I care?
-Oh, did you hear the news?
Choi, from the folding screen shop,
was banished.
The Chief State Councilor warned him
to never set foot in Bukchon again.
Huh. Whatever could he have done?
The youngest son of the councilor
is left-handed, is he not?
Just like Choi
from the folding screen shop.
So that's where his seed went?
My word, what an amusing place
this Bukchon is,
where such things happen every day.
Madam, Lord Cho Won is here.
Fine, let him…
Uh…
What? What did you say?
My lord,
the sample of tobacco I sent you
must have been pleasing indeed.
I could not forget its taste,
so I came to see you.
But I must confess,
the scent of these flowers is so strong…
…that I cannot remember the scent
of the tobacco I came to purchase.
Oh.
You may go now.
I must attend to my esteemed guest.
Goodbye, my lady.
Go on now. All of you.
I wrote to you so long ago,
yet you did not come to see me.
I thought I should quite perish
with yearning.
So that is why you dared to send
so brazen a letter as that.
Did you not tell me once
that you liked that I was fearless?
And that it was for that very reason
you held me deep in your embrace.
Brazen or not,
it seems this letter
has brought you to me once again.
You…
have no idea how meddlesome
those scrawlings have proven to be
or how much trouble that scrap of paper
may still cause me.
You never even thought of that, did you?
Bun-hui.
I am always worrying
about this wet tongue of yours.
If used unwisely,
it could become a noose around your neck.
And yet,
you so delight in wagging it,
you do not seem to care.
You speak as though
my letter were a matter of life and death.
Bun-hui.
If you do care about your daughter,
you would do well
to put your brazenness aside.
It would be all the easier to peek
at the scholar-officials you admire so.
And if you do play it right,
you may even join the ranks
of those wives you envy.
If you truly wish
to enter Bukchon society…
you must learn to behave
as though you have neither heard…
nor seen what you have.
Do remember that, Bun-hui.
My lord, please forgive me.
Please forgive us.
My mother's brush is clumsy.
I was the one
to copy the letter from her hand.
If it displeased you,
I beg your pardon on her behalf.
I swear, until the day I die,
no word of this matter
shall pass beyond these walls.
I swear it to you, my lord.
Amazing…
To think a mother
had her own daughter copy such a letter.
My father is all that binds us.
To honor that bond,
I had no choice but to obey my mother.
But if I had it my way, I'd have
nothing to do with that filthy wench.
Fine porcelain for sale!
Fine porcelain for sale! Fine… Yes, sir?
Your mother seemed to know
quite a bit about paintings.
Do you share her eye as well?
What?
Oh, I am no judge of what is good or bad.
I can only judge
if something is expensive.
Really?
In that case,
what do you make of this painting?
Will it fetch a decent price?
Hmm…
It looks as though
the flowers are swaying in the breeze,
and the scent of peonies
is practically wafting off the paper.
The tiny flower buds here,
behind the leaves,
are so adorable that I want to reach out
and put them in my hair.
This is a very important occasion
for His Lordship,
as he has long been away from court.
Ah…
Uh…
Here.
If you and I work together
and have this flower painting completed
upon His Lordship's return,
it would be a most wonderful way
to show him our support.
Your handwriting was very lovely,
but firm.
I was deeply impressed by it.
Let's complete this with your writing.
Any message will do.
Mm-hmm.
THE WHITE PEONY IN FULL BLOOM IS
Why, this is an entirely different style.
You've changed it for the painting.
To think you could
so alter your handwriting
to better suit
the piece's whimsical nature.
It would seem we have
a remarkable young lady in the house.
I have committed a sin!
Pray, have mercy and spare me, madam.
In truth, I did not write the copies.
Young Master In-ho did.
Young Master In-ho of the Kwon house?
The Left State Councilor's son?
Forgive me. No, just kill me.
How dare I, a mere concubine!
At any rate, now it is all over.
Oh, the young master
has already learned what I am.
And now…
Hmm…
Poor thing.
Being in one man's arms
when your heart is with another.
It must have weighed so heavily on you.
Madam?
When the young master found out,
did he refuse to acknowledge you at all?
I told him. And I have not seen him since.
Oh.
I fear for your heart,
which is delicate as a flower petal.
Listen to me.
As long as you serve
His Lordship dutifully,
I can turn a blind eye in such matters.
I am not unaware of how difficult
life can be for a woman in Bukchon.
Madam.
Tell me.
There's no one else
who knows about this, is there?
Mal-ttong is the only one who…
Lord Cho Won has a passing knowledge
of the matter.
Oh, goodness.
I would go to my cousin.
-What?
-I would go to him and beg for mercy.
He knows what spring is for a woman.
If your plea to him
is sufficiently heartfelt,
he will surely set his duty aside,
and look the other way.
T-Truly? Do you think he will?
If I were to guess,
he would gladly be a bridge
between you and Master In-ho.
Oh.
Mmm.
Oh. Oh, my lord.
Um, I have something to say to you.
Right now?
Yes.
Very well.
A letter?
This may take a while.
Do you think it is suitable
to leave your shoes outside in plain view?
Hmm?
What I mean is…
do you think it is wise to allow
someone else to see that you are here?
Um, my lord.
The young master has found out
that I am a concubine of this house.
You kept it secret?
I did not mean to.
At any rate,
what should I write?
How can I make him forgive me?
My…
You do rather look like her.
Like who?
Luckily for you,
I am somewhat of a master in this area.
A master?
"How could you…
only brush my shoulders and pass on?
I think of you, young master,
and find the breath caught in my chest.
I was wet all through the night,
and left in quite a state."
"Breathe"?
Um, my lord.
How do you spell the word "breathe" again?
Is there another "E" at the end, or not?
That's it.
You did spell it right.
"My legs keep spreading apart.
If only I had a pair of large hands
to take hold of them."
"I long for you.
You are in my thoughts tonight,
young master."
"When I see you next…
I expect you to scold my womanhood."
"I beg this of you."
Yes, there it is.
And what shall you do next?
Imagine, if you will,
that I am Young Master In-ho.
What shall you do to appease my anger?
Young master.
It is I, So-ok.
Young mas… I…
Please do not leave, young master!
Oh, why?
Why, oh, why?
What cruel aberration is this?
It is I, So-ok!
-So-ok.
-A concubine?
From the day we could not see each other,
I could not sleep.
I was thinking of you, young master.
My lady.
There is not an ounce of falsehood
in what you have said.
There couldn't be.
Oh.
I feel the same way.
I, too…
have been thinking of you, my lady.
I, too, have spent many sleepless nights
in heartrending agony.
On this moonlit night…
that which we longed for…
and carefully folded away…
I wish to unfold here and now together.
I wish for the same.
Unfold to your heart's content.
Allow me to begin.
Very well then.
We are growing ever so close, my lady.
Indeed.
The Young Master In-ho,
who you longed for,
is here for you now.
As is your So-ok.
My lady.
Now, then.
Your hand.
Right.
I would like my young master to begin.
Yes, my lady.
Young master.
Oh, my…
About the flower bud
you sent me last night.
Before I even laid a hand on her,
she was already half-naked.
I nearly lost my wits
and allowed the chase
-to end anticlimactically.
-It is I, So-ok, madam.
But I am still myself.
If I were to simply grant you
what you desire,
I feared our wager would become
a rather hollow affair.
Somehow I managed to send her away.
Did you sleep well last night, madam?
For now,
I shall focus on my original goal
of conquering the young widow.
Wait for me, dear cousin.
I look forward to claiming
that irresistible reward of yours.
Let me see.
"It was merely
a harmless jape, therefore"…
Ah. Oh, master, what took you so long?
You're supposed to stand
while you wait for me,
you insolent creature.
Here. Go and deliver this to the lady.
The lady has already left,
and took Eun-sil.
She went to Hwaseong to visit family.
What's this all about anyhow?
Late last night,
the late Lord An appeared to me
in a dream.
He said he wished to see you.
He reached out his hand,
and held tight to mine.
I suppose he must have been missing you.
Go and visit your parents' house.
Oh! Eun-sil! Eun-sil!
Eun-sil! Oh!
Eun-sil!
Madam! Madam!
Madam! Oh, madam!
Lord Cho Won is here.
Did you hear what I said?
The lord, Cho Won,
has come all the way here.
Madam.
You're here. I'll just--
What is this? Come now!
What is the meaning of this?
Oh, my lady.
Well, Eun-sil, tell me,
have you informed the lady I am here?
-Yes.
-Oh, good.
And what did she say?
That you have no reason to be here,
and you should go back at once.
Oh. Uh…
That's…
That cannot be.
That simply cannot be true.
-Go get her.
-Tell your lady again.
Tell her I will not take a single step…
Look.
…until she agrees to come out and face me.
She did as she pleased,
leaving without a word,
so I will do as I please as well.
I will wait for her.
See that you relay
exactly what I have said.
My lord, please do not do this to her.
Please go back at once.
What if the master of this house
should see you?
I'm sorry.
Come now! Tell her as I said!
Madam, if you're going to be like this,
you may as well see him.
He is still here. He hasn't left.
I hope he hasn't frozen in the rain.
Get away! Go, go!
Hurry up and go! Go!
Cho Won, that rascal.
What was he intending by making you
write a letter of explanation for him?
Out with it.
Mother, I swear,
I don't know anything, really.
All I know is Lord Cho Won
sought me out this morning.
He said if I did not write what he wanted,
he would ensure
disgrace came to our family.
I was worried that some misfortune
might befall you if I refused,
so I did as he told me to do.
Think about it, Mother.
Why would a man like him explain himself?
Really.
You said it yourself, Mother. I'm…
I'm an unbecoming and ill-bred girl.
For heaven's sake.
Why would he explain himself to me?
I just did as I was told, Mother.
Please believe me.
So-ok may know what's going on.
Why would So-ok know?
Because that is Cho Won's cousin's house.
Go over there to eavesdrop
and find out what you can.
Go find out the reason why Cho Won
made you do such a ridiculous thing!
Could you, for one fleeting moment,
show me a glimpse of your face, my lady?
I shall continue to wait here!
I wish only to show you my heart…
…but you will not see it.
Hey, Chil-seong. This is it.
Eun-sil.
W-Where is she?
The night is most cold.
You should go back to your home, my lord.
Are you all right, my lady?
I wanted you to have this letter.
That is all. Please read it.
You will find in this letter…
my truest feelings.
It is proof
that my feelings are not false.
But I…
I cannot leave like this.
I must clear
the misunderstanding between us.
Oh, please.
Will you not take this letter?
I had thought our two hearts were one.
I had thought my heart…
desired the same thing as yours.
Indeed, I did.
And yet…
Oh, if you will not let me
tell this to you,
what on earth am I to do?
Why?
Why did you appear before me?
Why did you appear
to a lowly creature such as I?
Was it to kill me?
Why have you…
made me long for you?
Because…
I want to live, my lord.
My lady.
I swear to you…
I will keep you alive…
no matter the cost…
if it's the last thing I do.